Register of the Evgenii Miller Papers, 1916-1924
Hoover Institution Archives
Evgenii Miller Papers,
1916-1924
28007
Miller, Evgenii Karlovich, 1867-1937
20 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 album box, 17 envelopes (12.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, orders, printed matter, and photographs, relating to White Russian military and diplomatic activities during the Russian Civil War, Bolshevik atrocities, and White Russian refugees
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1928.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (23 reels).
Access Points
Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich, baron, 1878-1928; Russia (Territory under White armies, 1918-1920) Armiia--Officers; France; France--Foreign relations--Soviet Union; Soviet Union; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Foreign relations--France; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Refugees; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920; Refugees; Russians in foreign countries
Biographical Note
1867 Born, Dvinsk, Russia
1886 Graduated, Nikolaevskoe Kavaleriiskoe Uchilishche, St. Petersburg. Assigned to Leib-gvardii Gusarskii Polk, TSarskoe Selo
1898-1907 Russian Military Agent in Belgium, Holland and Italy
1910-1912 Director of Nikolaevskoe Kavaleriiskoe Uchilishche
1912-1914 Chief-of-Staff of the Moscow Military Region
1914-1917 Chief-of-Staff of the Russian Fifth Army and Commander of the Twenty-Sixth Army Corps Promoted to Lieutenant-General Arrested and wounded by rebel soldiers during Revolution
1918 Placed in charge of demobilizing Russian troops on the Western Front by Russian Ambassador to France Vasilii Maklakov
1919-1920 Appointed Governor-General of Arkhangel'sk Region by Nikolai CHaikovskii and Commander-in-Chief of anti-Bolshevik Northern Armies by Admiral V. Kolchak
1920-1922 Military and Naval Representative of Gen. Petr Vrangel' in Paris
1924-1937 Commander of the First Section of the Russkii Obshche-Voinskii Soiuz (R.O.V.S). After the kidnapping of Lieut.-Gen. Aleksandr Kutepov by the O.G.P.U, assumed chairmanship of whole organization
1937 Kidnapped by Soviet agents on the streets of Paris. Taken to Moscow, condemned to death and shot on orders of the N.K.V.D.
Series Description
- Writings, 1917-1924 (Box No. 1.)
  Testimony of Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller given to Gen. Lavr Kornilov's Commission and report to French ambassador and foreign press re situation in Russia.
- Subject File, 1918-1924 (Box No. 1.-20)
  Papers belonging to the office of the Voennyi Agent vo Frantsii, Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller. Includes material related to Russkii Ekspeditsionnyi Korpus vo Frantsii; administrative matters; correspondence with Russian Military Agents in other countries and Russian Army General Headquarters; intelligence and other reports about the Soviet Union and European countries in which refugees resided; material related to Russian refugees, especially military, including problems of their legal status abroad, employment, transportation, material support, medical aid and education. Lieut.-Gen. Nikolai Golovin's original arrangement of the collection into files has been retained. However, material within each file has been described in greater detail and arranged within each file, either by subject or physical form.
- Photographs, 1916-1923 (Box No. 21.)
  71 prints and 7 glass negatives. Includes photographs collected as evidence by the Osobaia Komissiia po razsledovaniiu zlodeianii bol'shevikov, sostoiashchei pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Vooruzhennymi Silami na IUge Rossii depicting Bolshevik atrocities committed during the Civil War and photographs of Russian Army officers abroad. Arranged by subject.
Container List
- WRITINGS, 1917-1924. See also SUBJECT FILE/Group I, File 38M
  - "Pokazaniia Gen.-Leitenanta E. K. Millera, K.-ra 26 arm. Korpusa, dannyia im Sledstvennoi Komissii 20-28 aprelia 1917 goda, naznachennoi Glavnokomanduiushchim Petr. V. Okruga Generalom Kornilovym, po prikazaniiu Voennago Ministra Guchkova" (Box 1.)
    - Typescript (Folder 1)
    - Photocopy (Folder 2)
  - "Memoire". Typescript
    - 1918 (Folder 3)
    - 1924. Revised version (Folder 4)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1924
  - (Group I, File 1M)
    - Russkii Legion vo Frantsii. Day-orders. Hand-written and mimeograph
      - Miscellaneous locations
        - 1918 (Folder 5-8)
        - 1919 (Folder 9)
      - Depot, Laval, 1918 (Folder 10-15)
  - (Group I, File 2M)
    - Tylovoe Upravlenie Russkikh voisk vo Frantsii. Day-orders, 1917 August-1918 February. Mimeograph (Folder 16-18)
  - (Group I, File 3M) (Box 2.)
    - Russkie Voiska vo Frantsii. Day-orders, 1917 September-November. Mimeograph (Folder 1-3)
    - Vtoraia Osobaia pekhotnaia diviziia. Day-orders, 1918 January-March. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - (Group I, File 4M)
    - Komitet po obezpecheniiu vysshago obrazovaniia russkomu iunoshestvu. Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. Ivan KHolmnsen and Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller with Mikhail Fedorov re placement of former military personnel in institutions of higher learning, 1922 January-1923 November. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 5-6)
    - Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet v Parizhe. Minutes of meetings, 1923 January-December. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 7-10)
  - (Group I, File 5M)
    - Finland. Reports and excerpts from newspapers, 1920. Typescript (Folder 11-12)
    - Kronstadt Rebellion, 1921. Includes reports, telegrams, proclamations and radio messages of rebels. Typescript (Folder 13-14)
    - Severo-Zapadnaia Armiia of Lieut.-Gen. Nikolai IUdenich. Includes correspondence of Lieut-Gens. Evgenii Miller, Nikolai Monkevich, Nikolai Kliuev and Col. Dimitrii Kandaurov; reports and printed matter re conditions of internment in Finland, Estonia and Latvia; evacuation of army to the Balkans and the Crimea. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 15-22)
    - Ukraine (Box 3.)
      - Correspondence between Lieut.-Gen. Andrei Rodzianko and Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller, 1921 (Folder 1)
      - Reports
        - General
          - "Zapiska po ukrainskomu voprosu", 1921. Typescript (Folder 2)
          - "Svedeniia po ukrainskomu voprosu", 1922. Typescript (Folder 3)
        - Makhrov, Petr Lieut.-Gen., "Voennyi obzor za Noiabr' 1920". Typescript (Folder 4)
  - (Group I, File 6M)
    - Poland. Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia v Pol'she. Material related to the formation of the Russian Third Army, 1919 March-1920 December. Typescript and handwritten
      - Correspondence of and about Gens. Bredov, Balakhovich, Glazenap and Boboshko; Russian Military Representative in Paris Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Miller, Russian Military Representative in Poland, Gen. Petr Makhrov and Russian Military Representatives Generals Gerua, KHolmnsen and Pototskii; diplomatic representative Girs and Foreign Minister Petr Struve; V.S.IU.R. headquarters and Gen. Petr Vrangel'; negotiations with Polish government and Boris Savinkov re alliance with Petliura and united military front against the Bolsheviks; effect of separate peace between Ukraine and Bolsheviks; contacts with French military and government agencies (Folder 5-11)
      - Reports. Mostly intelligence reports re condition and movements of armies in Finland, the Baltics, Poland and the Ukraine (Folder 12-14)
  - (Group I, File 7M)
    - Poland. Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia v Pol'she, 1921 January-March
      - General
        - Belukha-Kokhanovskii, Deitrikh Capt. Report to Chief-of-Staff of Russian Army re Third Army. Typescript (Folder 15)
        - Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia v Pol'she
          - Correspondence. Includes correspondence of Gen. Petr Makhrov (Folder 16-17)
          - Reports. Typescript (Folder 18)
        - Russkii politicheskii evakutsionnyi Komitet. Correspondence. Typescript (Folder 19)
        - Sovet po delam internirovannykh v Pol'she
          - Minutes of meetings. Typescript (Folder 20-21)
          - Orders. Typescript (Folder 22)
      - Maps. Disposition of Polish, White Russian and Bolshevik troops on western front, 1921 March
      - Printed matter
        - Clippings. Writings of Boris Savinkov (Folder 23)
        - Summaries of Polish newspapers. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - (Group I, File 8M) (Box 4.)
    - Poland. Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia v Pol'she, 1921 April-December
      - Correspondence
        - Makhrov, Petr Lieut.-Gen. and Lieut.-Gen. Pavel SHatilov,V.S.I.U.R. General Staff. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 1)
        - Miller, Evgenii Lieut.-Gen.
          - CHaikovskii, Nikolai. Typescript (Folder 2)
          - Makhrov, Petr Lieut.-Gen. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 3-5)
          - Russkii politicheskii evakutsionnyi Komitet. Typescript (Folder 6)
        - Savinkov, Boris. Typescript and mimeograph (Folder 7)
      - Lists of personnel receiving aid, Third Russian Army and "Diviziia Smerti" Narodno-Dobrovol'cheskaia Armiia. Typescript (Folder 8)
      - Orders. Russkii politicheskii evakutsionnyi Komitet. Mimeograph (Folder 9)
      - Press. Summaries of Belorussian and Polish press. Typescript (Folder 10)
      - Reports. Typescript (Folder 11-12)
  - (Group I, File 9M)
    - Poland. Rossiiskaia Voennaia Missiia v Pol'she, 1921 December-1923 September
      - General. "Narod.-Dobr. Armiia 1920". Mimeograph journal (Folder 13)
      - Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. Petr Makhrov. Typescript and handwritten
        - General (Folder 14)
        - KHolmnsen, Ivan Lieut.-Gen. (Folder 15-17)
        - Miller, Evgenii Lieut.-Gen. (Folder 18-19)
        - Obshchestvo pomoshchi russkim bezhentsam v Pol'she (M.K.K.) (Folder 20)
      - Reports. Includes material re internment camps (Tukhol' and others) for Russian military and civilian refugees in Poland. Typescipt (Folder 21)
  - (Group I, File 10M) (Box 5.)
    - Switzerland. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v SHveitsarii, 1919 January-October
      - Correspondence and reports of Major-Gen. Sergei Golovan (Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v SHveitsarii) to Lieut.-Gen. Nikolai Golovin (Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent vo Frantsii) and Lieut.-Gen. Dmitrii SHcherbachev (Shtab). Includes material re Bolshevik activity in Switzerland and Germany; Turkish contacts with Muslim territories of former Russian Empire; political and military situation in the Ukraine, the Baltic States and Poland. Also includes press summaries and clippings (Folder 1-6)
  - (Group I, File 11M)
    - Switzerland. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v SHveitsarii, 1919 October-1920 February. Same as above (Folder 7-11)
  - (Group I, File 12M)
    - Switzerland. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v SHveitsarii, 1920 June-December
      - Correspondence re personnel matters. Includes material re transfer of officers to Crimea and aid to invalid officers and their families. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 12)
      - Reports. Same as above (Folder 13-16)
  - (Group I, File 13M) (Box 6.)
    - Italy. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Italii, 1920 March-1921 December
      - Correspondence of Col. Prince Aleksandr Volkonskii and Capt. Den' (Rossiiskie Voennye Agenty v Italii) re personnel, financial and office matters. Includes material re transfer of Russian military personnel to Crimea. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 1-4)
      - Reports of Col. Prince Aleksandr Volkonskii. Includes reports re political situation in Italy. Typescript (Folder 5)
    - Greece. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Gretsii, 1921 April-June
      - Correspondence, reports and press summaries of Col. Poliakov (Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Gretsii) re situation of Russian military and civilian refugees in Greece. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 6)
      - Reports. Stratigos, X., Expose general de la situation militaire and La campagne d'Asie-Mineure, 1921. Printed copies (Folder 7)
  - (Group I, File 14M)
    - Denmark. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Danii, 1919 June-1921 December
      - Correspondence of Maj.-Gen. Sergei Pototskii (Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Danii) and Col. Aleksei von Lampe re personnel, financial and office matters. Includes material re transfer of Russian military personnel to Crimea. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 8-10)
      - Reports of Maj.-Gen. Sergei Pototskii and Col. Aleksei von Lampe. Includes material re political situation and Bolshevik activity in Scandinavia, the Baltic States and Germany. Typescript (Folder 11-14)
  - (Group I, File 15M)
    - Czechoslovakia. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v CHekhoslovakii, 1920 May-June 1922 June
      - Correspondence of Major-Gen. M. Leontiev (Voennyi Agent v CHekhoslovakii). Includes office correspondence and material related to condition and political status of Russian military and civilian refugees; transfer of Russian military personnel to Crimea; repatriation of inmates in prisoner of war camps to the Soviet Union; situation of Cossacks. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 15-17)
      - Reports. Includes material re activity of Bolsheviks in Czechoslovakia; status of Russian refugees; summaries and clippings of Czech press. Typescript (Box 7., Folder 1-4)
  - (Group I, File 16M)
    - Great Britain. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Velikobritanii, 1920 Jan.-1923 Nov.
      - Correspondence
        - General office correspondence of Maj.-Gen. Boris Gartman, (Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Velikobritanii) especially re financial matters. Also includes material re transfer of Russian military personnel to Crimea and miscellaneous matters re situation of Russian officers and their families in Great Britain. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 5-11)
        - Status of naval property from Arkhangel'sk campaign. Typescript (Folder 12)
      - Reports. Includes material re political situation in Great Britain and Bolshevik activity in Germany. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - (Group I, File 17M)
    - Germany. Nachal'nik Delegatsii po delam russkikh voennoplennykh i bezhentsev v Germanii, 1920-1921
      - Correspondence of Maj.-Gen. Ivan KHolmnsen re situation of Russian military refugees from Poland (Gen. Bredov's Army); Red Army prisoners interned in Germany, activity of Soviet Representative Viktor Kopp and problem of repatriation to the Soviet Union; transfer of officers from Armies of the Northwest to Crimea, negotiations for transit visas and financial support. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 14-21)
      - Reports re political situation in Germany. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - (Group I, File 18M) (Box 8.)
    - United States. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Soedinennykh SHtatakh Ameriki, 1920-1921
      - Correspondence of Col. Aleksandr Nikolaev. Includes general office correspondence; material related to purchase of war supplies and matters concerning Russian officers in the United States. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 1-6)
      - Report re political situation in the United States. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - (Group I, File 19M)
    - Japan. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v IAponii, 1920 Sept.- 1921 Dec.
      - Podtiagin, Mikhail, Maj.-Gen., (Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v IAponii)
        - Correspondence. Includes general office correspondence; information re government monies in possession of Ataman Semenov; military personnel matters, including KHabarovskii and Sibirskii Kadetskii Korpus. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 8-9)
        - Press summaries from Japanese press related to Russian matters. Typescript (Folder 10)
        - Reports re situation in the Far East, Siberia and Japan. Typescript (Folder 11)
      - Semenov, Grigorii, Ataman
        - General. Includes appeals and oaths of allegiance to Ataman Semenov of various cossack and peasant groups; protocols of meetings of the Amur Cossack Army; military orders of Ataman Semenov (Folder 12-14)
        - Correspondence of his office in Tokyo. Typescript (Folder 15)
        - Printed matter
          - "K narodam Rossii i k russkim liudiam", Dec. 1920 (Folder 16)
          - "Appel aux Peuples du Monde", 1921 (Folder 17)
        - Reports re Amur region, Siberia, Republic of the Far East (Dal'ne-Vostochnaia Respublika), Transbaikal region; intelligence operations; situation of White Movement in the Far East; speech of V. Ivanov at Conference of non-Socialist organizations in Vladivostok (S"ezd nesotsialisticheskikh organizatsii). Typescript (Folder 18-20)
  - (Group I, File 20M) (Box 9.)
    - Romania. Voennyi Predstavitel' v Rumynii Glavnokomanduiushchago V.S.IU.R., 1921 Jan.-Dec. 1923 Dec.
      - Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. Aleksandr Gerua. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 1-2)
      - Reports. Includes information re situation in the Soviet Union. Typescript (Folder 3-4)
    - Serbia. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Korolevstve Serbov, KHorvatov i Sloventsev and Rossiiskii Poslannik v Korolevstve Serbov, KHorvatov i Sloventsev, 1920 Aug.-1923 Dec.
      - Correspondence of Vasilii SHtrandtman and Maj.-Gen. Dmitrii Pototskii. Includes general office correspondence; negotiations for transit visas to the Crimea for officers of Gen. Nikolai IUdenich's army; establishment of camps and search for employment for military refugees; condition of Military School in Sarajevo; Red Cross aid to refugees. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 5-8)
      - Reports. Typescript
        - General. Includes material re transit of officers from army of Gen. Nikolai IUdenich and supply of refugees by Red Cross (Folder 9)
        - List of Russian military regalia brought to Serbia by Col. Kolobov (Folder 10)
  - (Group I, File 21M)
    - Sweden and Norway. Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v SHvetsii i Norvegii, 1920-1921
      - General. Treaty between Estonia and Lieut.-Gen. P. Glazenap on behalf of Severo-Zapadnaia Armiia, 1920 Feb. Typescript copy (Folder 11)
      - Correspondence
        - General. Includes general office correspondence of Col. Dmitrii Kandaurov. Also includes material re condition of military refugees from Severo-Zapadnaia Armiia of Gen. Nikolai IUdenich in Finland and the Baltic; exploitation of Russian prisoners of war in Estonian camps; negotiations for transit visas for transfer of Russian officers to the Crimea; questions re military supplies of Severo-Zapadnaia Armiia. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 12-19)
        - IUdenich, Nikolai Lieut.-Gen. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 20)
      - Press. Summaries and clippings from European press. Typescript and printed matter (Folder 21)
      - Reports
        - General (Folder 22)
        - Evseev, I., "Zapiska o polozhenii rabochikh na lesnykh rabotakh", 1920. Typescript (Folder 23)
        - "Postanovlenie", Osobaia Komissiia po revizii tylovykh uchrezhdenii...Severo-Zapadnoi Armii, 1920. Typescript (Folder 24)
    - (Group I, File 22M) (Box 10.)
      - Rossiiskie Diplomaticheskie Predstaviteli, 1920-1921
        - Correspondence
          - Allied forces (Folder 1)
          - Bulgaria (Folder 2)
          - Diplomatic. Includes transcripts of telegrams and other correspondence between Boris Bakhmetev, Nikolai de Basili, Mikhail Girs, Gorlov, Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Hermonius, V. Krupenskii, Vasilii Maklakov, Anatolii Neratov, Vasilii SHtrandtman and Petr Struve. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 3-15)
          - Repatriation and resettlement of Russian troops. Includes correspondence with Gen. Pelle (Folder 16)
          - Supplies for Vrangel's Army in the Crimea. Includes munitions and medical supplies (Folder 17)
  - (Group III, File 23M)
    - Bulgaria. Voennyi Predstavitel' v Bolgarii, Nachal'nik Snabzheniia Russkoi Armii and Rossiiskaia Missiia v Bolgarii, 1923 Nov.- 1924 Sept.
      - Correspondence, especially related to situation of Russian military and civilian refugees. Includes material of Komitet po delam russkikh bezhentsev v Bolgarii and Russkaia Stroitel'naia Kontora. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 18-23)
      - Reports
        - General (Folder 24)
        - Dobrinovich, (?), "Doklad gospodinu Ministru Vnutrennikh Del i Narodnago Zdraviia". Typescript (Folder 25)
  - (Group III, File 24M) (Box 11.)
    - Bulgaria. Voennyi Predstavitel' v Bolgarii, Nachal'nik Snabzheniia Russkoi Armii and Rossiiskaia Missiia v Bolgarii, 1921-1924
      - Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. Evgenii Viazmitinov, (Voennyi Predstavitel' v Bolgarii), A. Petriaev, (Rossiiskaia Missiia v Bolgarii) and Lieut-Gen. Petr Stavitski, (Nachal'nik Snabzheniia Russkoi Armii). Also includes correspondence of Mikhail Girs, Lieut.-Gen. Ivan KHolmnsen, Maj.-Gen. Pavel Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. Ivan Ronzhin, Boris Serafimov, Lieut.-Gen. Pavel SHatilov and Gen. Weygand related to the resettlement of Russian military contingents in Bulgaria and their financial support. Includes material of Komitet po delam russkikh bezhentsev v Bolgarii and the Red Cross. Typescript and handwritten (Folder 1-8)
      - Printed matter. Rus', 1923 June 10. Printed copy (Folder 9)
      - Reports. Typescript
        - General (Folder 10)
        - Nachal'nik informatsionnago otdeleniia shtaba, "Znachenie ukrainskago voprosa dlia nastoiiashchago momenta", July 1921 (Folder 11)
        - Podchertkov, Col., "Ot russkago natsional'nago komiteta" (Folder 12)
        - Vitkovskii, Lieut.-Gen., "Svodka ob obstanovke v mestakh raspolozheniia russkikh garnizonov i rabochikh partii" (Folder 13)
  - (Group III, File 25M)
    - Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta and other humanitarian organizations, 1921-1924
      - General
        - General. Individual charity cases. Includes requests for aid and inquiries re individuals (Folder 14)
        - Komitet o Pomoshchi Tuberkuleznym. Appeal. Typescript (Folder 15)
        - Komitet Pomoshchi Russkim Invalidam
          - Appeals
            - Printed (Folder 16)
            - Typescript (Folder 17)
          - Minutes of meetings. Typescript (Folder 18)
          - Statement of purpose and organizational matters. Typescript (Folder 19)
        - Russkie Gumanitarnye Organizatsii v Parizhe. Minutes of meeting. Typescript (Folder 20)
        - Soveshchanie po Delam o Bezhentsakh. Correspondence and minutes of meetings. Includes correspondence of Mikhail Girs and material related to League of Nations (Folder 21)
      - Correspondence
        - General. Includes Nikolai Astrov, Lieut.-Gen. Nikolai Baratov, Boris Ivanitskii, Lieut.-Gen. Ivan KHolmnsen. Also Soiuz Russkikh Invalidov za Granitsei and Zemsko-Gorodskoi Komitet (Folder 22)
        - Estonia (Folder 23)
      - Minutes of meetings (Folder 24)
  - (Group III, File 26M) (Box 12.)
    - Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta
      - General
        - Individual charity cases. Includes requests for aid and inquiries re individuals (Folder 1-5)
        - Refugees in Marseille under care of Red Cross and repatriation of former Russian prisoners of war by French government (Folder 6)
      - Correspondence re aid to Russian war invalids in exile. Includes material re officers of Sever-Zapadnaia Armiia in Estonia (Folder 7-9)
      - Printed matter
        - General. Miscellaneous material re relief of St. Petersburg (Folder 10)
        - British Committe of the Russian Red Cross Fund in Great Britain, First Report 1919-1921 (Folder 11)